[{"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acd8", "question": "Who first became president of France in 1995?", "answer": "Jacques Chirac", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ecaea45790ded87bb38fd8e", "question": "When measured from its underwater base, what is the tallest mountain?", "answer": "Mauna Kea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59067e76ff9c0647b50a807a", "question": "Who was awarded the 2016 Nobel Prize for Literature?", "answer": "Bob Dylan", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5febd5ec7e83c707845b2168", "question": "The musical score for Hitchcock's \"Psycho\" uses which instrument exclusively?", "answer": "Stringed instruments", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ab1", "question": "What writer of Vampires and Ghosts wrote, A Magical Christmas in 1997?", "answer": "Heather Graham", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a682", "question": "Which states share a border with South Carolina?", "answer": "Georgia and North Carolina", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0f3", "question": "October 22, 1692 marked the last time a person in America was hanged for what crime?", "answer": "Witchcraft", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff514e3ff04d658268c92e5", "question": "What actor was one of the most decorated American combat soldiers of World War II?", "answer": "Audie Murphy\u00a0received every military combat award for valor available from the U.S. Army, including the Medal of Honor.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c06d", "question": "In what decade was Montreal Canadien great Maurice \"Rocket\" Richard born?", "answer": "1920s", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b49", "question": "Where did the Pied Piper play?", "answer": "Hamelin", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339664", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", Marge decided to sell what snack food?", "answer": "Pretzels", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133983a", "question": "Who won a Grammy Award for his album \"Come Dance With Me\"?", "answer": "Frank Sinatra", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133998b", "question": "What was the name of the main police detective played by Jack Webb on the TV show \"Dragnet\"?", "answer": "Joe Friday", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a25ef3d6682715b82711cd5", "question": "The Mayflower is famous for being the first ship to transport what to the New World?", "answer": "English Puritans", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396ba", "question": "Which Seinfeld character takes his shirt off when he visits the toilet?", "answer": "George Costanza", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5909d0fabb53d1af658864ff", "question": "What is the main ingredient in traditional gingerbread cookies?", "answer": "Flour", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aaba", "question": "What is the capital of Solomon Islands?", "answer": "Honiara", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a16", "question": "What is Bridget Jones' home city?", "answer": "London", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff3c1fd4f032c0db195b47c", "question": "What war lasted approximately 38 minutes?", "answer": "The\u00a0Anglo-Zanzibar War", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5c88e87222f44c2d77a29c47", "question": "Where is the deepest land gorge in the US?", "answer": "Along the border of eastern Oregon, eastern Washington and western Idaho", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba91", "question": "In what year did Mattel introduce the Ken Doll to complement Barbie?", "answer": "1961", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff3c3314f032c0db195b48b", "question": "Who was a primary force behind the Reign of Terror?", "answer": "Robespierre", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fff", "question": "Who wrote the best selling novel \"Polo\"?", "answer": "Jilly cooper", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc99", "question": "What sport's lingo uses the term \"Googly\"?", "answer": "Cricket", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339536", "question": "What TV show featured Ellen DeGeneres as a receptionist?", "answer": "Open House", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8b40201dd7bf43be5e7b9", "question": "What library has the most books in the U.S.?", "answer": "The Library of Congress", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd2d47d2596a59cbdfbd3a4", "question": "Where will you find the lacrimal bone?", "answer": "Face", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b7f", "question": "Who played Kate Austen on the ABC series \"Lost\"?", "answer": "Evangeline Lilly", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd970a323c87fd04dd15e48", "question": "Which U.S. president was the first to leave the country while in office?", "answer": "Theodore Roosevelt", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58dba522874c93a3298b214d", "question": "What country is credited with inventing the modern, self-igniting match?", "answer": "France", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5cd40b9e685cf15b733e988a", "question": "In which county in the United Kingdom is the Glastonbury Festival held?", "answer": "Somerset", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca17", "question": "What is used to measure horizontal and vertical angles in surveying?", "answer": "A theodolite", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fea7835ff048f679a45abd5", "question": "What kind of electromagnetic radiation arises only from nuclear excitations?", "answer": "Gamma radiation", "category": "science"}, {"id": "590721743745b36be73039f7", "question": "What year did Charles Dickens publish a novella entitled \"A Christmas Carol\"?", "answer": "1843", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7a4", "question": "How old was astronaut Neil Armstrong when he passed away in 2012?", "answer": "82", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58f167a1f7c52aae91cc07bb", "question": "What country borders the Republic of Guinea-Bissau to the north?", "answer": "Senegal", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cf3", "question": "Where did Ichabod Crane reside?", "answer": "Sleepy Hollow", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a51a", "question": "The Banff Airport is located in which country?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f9d", "question": "In which river did the Pied Piper drown the rats of Hamelin?", "answer": "Weser", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a815", "question": "What European country is named in honor of the Dinaric Alps and their appearance?", "answer": "Montenegro", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf35", "question": "What number is at 12 o'clock on a dartboard?", "answer": "20", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c482", "question": "Are polar bears carnivores or omnivores?", "answer": "Carnivores", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd2d45b2596a59cbdfbd3a2", "question": "What cells are responsible for forming new bone?", "answer": "Osteoblasts", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fffa59773838c5c8a417f27", "question": "Ambergris is a waxy substance that originates as a secretion from what animal?", "answer": "Sperm whale", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe767e7eec85e375820b29a", "question": "What is the world's widest river?", "answer": "Amazon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b521", "question": "How loud is a vuvuzela?", "answer": "127 db", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fb3", "question": "Which two Spice Girls shared the same first name?", "answer": "Scary and Sporty", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6007845fbd51d85e222ab65a", "question": "What Benedictine monk invented champagne?", "answer": "Dom Pierre P\u00e9rignon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6010c8840775fa611bce67e1", "question": "\"Bona fide\" literally translates to what?", "answer": "Bona fide is Latin, and it literally translates to \"in good faith\".", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339477", "question": "Who played the role of David Dunn in the movie \"Unbreakable\"?", "answer": "Bruce Willis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff511daff04d658268c92cb", "question": "What Greek general is responsible for the project that generated most of the surviving structures on the Acropolis?", "answer": "Pericles\u00a0promoted the arts and literature, which made Athens the educational and cultural center of the ancient Greek world.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "601b4a2e49076251badbeab0", "question": "Where did the phrase \"Don\u2019t Mess With Texas\" come from?", "answer": "An anti-litter campaign -- The campaign idea was \u201cdon\u2019t litter in Texas, don\u2019t mess up Texas,\u201d but it became so much more.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab3f", "question": "Juba is the capital of which African country?", "answer": "South Sudan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b289", "question": "What 1977 hit was the theme of Bill Clinton's 1992 presidential campaign?", "answer": "Don't Stop by Fleetwood Mac", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b034", "question": "In what year did Adolf Hitler become Chancellor of Germany?", "answer": "1933", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c747", "question": "What element's chemical symbol are the letters \"Na\"?", "answer": "Sodium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ea1", "question": "The Broadway hit \"Rent\" translates what opera to a Greenwich Village apartment?", "answer": "La Boheme", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6013711e1381754895396389", "question": "Who was the original host of \"Wheel of Fortune\"?", "answer": "The original host was Chuck Woolery, a game show mainstay who left the show in 1981 over contract disputes.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b20f", "question": "Who was assassinated by Leon Czolgosz?", "answer": "William McKinley", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5cd40d5a685cf15b733e9892", "question": "Why did the Mongolians fail to invade Japan?", "answer": "Because of a typhoon called \"kamikaze\"", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a63a", "question": "West Virginia has a shoreline along which ocean?", "answer": "None", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d17", "question": "What newspaper editor wrote the headline \"Spider-Man: Threat or Menace\"?", "answer": "J. Jonah Jameson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339801", "question": "What looks like a saxophone but sounds like a harmonica?", "answer": "Goofus or Couesnophone", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6c1", "question": "Sigmund Freud believed a person\u2019s psyche was composed of what three components?", "answer": "Id, the ego and the super-ego", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133898d", "question": "What name did the meaner of Cinderella's stepsisters call her?", "answer": "Cinderwench", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2a2", "question": "Which general's father led the investigation of the Lindbergh baby kidnapping?", "answer": "Norman Schwarzkopf", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a07f", "question": "Which actor was the first to play Robin Hood on television?", "answer": "Patrick Troughton", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b083", "question": "In what year did \"Mad Magazine\" debut?", "answer": "1952", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ad1", "question": "What book is divided into 114 chapters called \"suras\"?", "answer": "The Qur'an", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff6673052a821ff76ae8afc", "question": "How much did Judas Iscariot receive for betraying Jesus Christ?", "answer": "\"30 pieces of silver\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9f8", "question": "What was the name of the first space-ready orbiter of NASA's space shuttle program?", "answer": "Columbia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5a4", "question": "Which US state was established by William Penn in 1681?", "answer": "Pennsylvania", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9c1", "question": "Tristram is the main town of which RPG game?", "answer": "Diablo", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133924c", "question": "What do the thieves set out to steal in the movie \"Reservoir Dogs?\"", "answer": "Diamonds", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388f3", "question": "What is Tchaikovsky's ballet \"Le Lac des Cygnes\" commonly called?", "answer": "Swan Lake", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395dd", "question": "Which \"Simpsons\" character has a superfluous third nipple?", "answer": "Krusty", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc2e", "question": "What year did Barbie doll first appear on the market?", "answer": "1959", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5f164e81f9b80650dbe7f934", "question": "What color is the \"Soul stone\" in the 2017 Marvel Legacy relaunch?", "answer": "Orange", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe6a47d20565ad31a57c7bd", "question": "Who was the first U.S. President born west of the Mississippi River?", "answer": "Herbert Hoover", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adf1", "question": "The month July is named for what historical leader?", "answer": "Julius Caesar", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b19c", "question": "What dog breed was the official 1972 Summer Olympics mascot?", "answer": "Dachshund", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abeb", "question": "Nyala are a type of antelope that are indigenous to which continent?", "answer": "Africa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af6c", "question": "The Camp David Accord negotiated peace between which two countries?", "answer": "Egypt and Israel", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac24", "question": "Which country borders Suriname to the south?", "answer": "Brazil", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b37c", "question": "Who was the 15th President of the US?", "answer": "James Buchanan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fefa6196ce05a3942286eca", "question": "In which city does the film \"Home Alone\" take place?", "answer": "Chicago", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b402", "question": "What year did the US first host the Summer Olympic Games?", "answer": "1904", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59ca3e2844f0f6af5b066646", "question": "In mathematics which prefix refers to 10 to the power of minus 12?", "answer": "Pico", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58f1683df7c52aae91cc07c4", "question": "What is the fear of light flashes known as?", "answer": "Selaphobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba70", "question": "Gouda cheese comes from what country?", "answer": "The Netherlands", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c49d", "question": "Self-rising flour contains what crucial ingredient?", "answer": "Baking powder", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fb086e4cf631c2414a13b55", "question": "In the TV show \"Friends\", what was the name of Ross and Monica\u2019s dog when they were kids?", "answer": "Chi Chi", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390e3", "question": "What is the middle name of author Arthur C. Clarke?", "answer": "Charles", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fdfbe6d003d27d341092bce", "question": "Where is the world-famous Skytree tower located?", "answer": "Tokyo", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe8f29901dd7bf43be5e811", "question": "What is the process of raising silkworms and making silk called?", "answer": "Sericulture", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab76", "question": "Port Louis is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Mauritius", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fb085fbcf631c2414a13b50", "question": "Who sings the \"Friends\" theme song?", "answer": "The Rembrandts", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8f9", "question": "Which chemical element is named after the Latin word for \"red\"?", "answer": "Rubidium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fbaec940738315b1fb74e2d", "question": "Early in what novel, is a rule made that only the person holding a conch shell may talk during group meetings?", "answer": "Lord of the Flies", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339388", "question": "What is the Voight-Kampff machine in the movie \"Blade Runner\"?", "answer": "A lie detector", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2f4", "question": "What US state has been governed by Gifford Pinchot and Milton Shapp?", "answer": "Pennsylvania", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fef96166ce05a3942286e9a", "question": "In what Disney movie would you find the character of Briar Rose?", "answer": "\"Sleeping Beauty\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be49", "question": "What is Port Salut?", "answer": "A type of cheese", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe69d1d20565ad31a57c775", "question": "How many U.S. states sit on land bought by the Louisiana Purchase?", "answer": "15", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c172", "question": "What does a dowser do?", "answer": "Find water", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396be", "question": "Which Spice girl was the only one named after a spice?", "answer": "Ginger", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4b30b06d333868d34d6d5", "question": "What Egyptian ruler sided with Mark Antony at the Battle of Actium?", "answer": "Cleopatra", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f5a", "question": "What New York cardiologist published his bestselling \"Diet Revolution\" in 1972?", "answer": "Robert Atkins", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b09b", "question": "Who was the first president to have been born after the American Revolution?", "answer": "Martin Van Buren", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59008c40cf842fa4c4ba969e", "question": "With which horror film series would you associate the character Leatherface?", "answer": "Texas Chainsaw Massacre", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecd174ec223966ae8f88bf", "question": "In \"Finding Nemo\", where is the dentist's diploma from?", "answer": "Pixar University", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffa42b5c73aa70ea0b70b14", "question": "Fort-de-France is the capital of what country?", "answer": "Martinique", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a495", "question": "Which Australian state borders all other mainland states?", "answer": "South Australia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba15", "question": "Who won a gold medal in men's figure skating at the 1988 Winter Olympics in Calgary?", "answer": "Brian Boitano", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fed265aec223966ae8f8909", "question": "In early 2019, Ariana Grande held the top three spots on the Billboard Hot 100. Who is the only other artist(s) to have achieved this feat prior to her?", "answer": "The Beatles", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff0b049e662d71a53650fc5", "question": "The roof of Spain\u2019s Dal\u00ed Theatre-Museum is lined with what?", "answer": "Eggs", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bea7", "question": "What flower symbolizes the throne of the Japanese emperor?", "answer": "The chrysanthemum", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fec8df7ec223966ae8f885a", "question": "What actor plays M. Gustave in the movie \"The Grand Budapest Hotel\"?", "answer": "Ralph Fiennes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcb0", "question": "What kind of fruit juice is used to mix a Bloody Mary?", "answer": "Tomato", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fedd9936ce05a3942286d79", "question": "What was Red good at doing in prison in the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "Smuggling contraband into the prison.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe76f66eec85e375820b2e9", "question": "Where can you see the so-called \"Horizontal Waterfalls\"?", "answer": "Australia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd2d2172596a59cbdfbd38a", "question": "What special power does the titular character possess in \"Matilda\"?", "answer": "Telekinesis", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fea37fbff048f679a45ab1f", "question": "Which psychological concept did Pavlov\u2019s dog help him describe?", "answer": "Conditioning", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58d116b84fea7fe947a22272", "question": "Who wrote the 1938 play \"The Corn Is Green\"?", "answer": "Emlyn Williams", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5bc1d99ed702eaa27a66982a", "question": "Which Swedish musician sang the song \"Save Tonight\"?", "answer": "Eagle-Eye Cherry", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339984", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what was the name of Barney's snowplowing business?", "answer": "Plow King", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea49efff048f679a45abbd", "question": "On which part of the body is an angioplasty performed?", "answer": "Blood vessel", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b74a", "question": "What kind of patterns are Dutchman's puzzle, log cabin and Irish chain?", "answer": "Quilts", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d10", "question": "What movie's first sequel featured the subtitle \"On the Rocks\"?", "answer": "Arthur", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1f8", "question": "Who chose her new name in 1953 to honor a Danish surgeon named Christian Hamburger?", "answer": "Christine Jorgensen", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6015e184fe83fe1f2a824b95", "question": "What happened at Dunkirk in May 1940?", "answer": "British forces retreated across the English Channel.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be0f", "question": "Why was Mary Mallon famous in the early 1900s for her signature dessert of peaches and ice cream?", "answer": "It gave people typhus", "category": "general"}, {"id": "596dfa93cf3977a46e7ce447", "question": "The Statue of Liberty was a gift resulting from the diplomatic relationship between the United States and what country?", "answer": "France", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe69fc820565ad31a57c790", "question": "Where did the \u201cwiki\u201d in Wikipedia come from?", "answer": "Hawaiian for \"fast\" or \"quick\"", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1c5", "question": "Who was the US Green Party's first presidential candidate?", "answer": "Ralph Nader", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393ee", "question": "According to the 1973 movie, soylent green is what?", "answer": "People", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393e8", "question": "What country singer recorded a popular album at Folsom Prison?", "answer": "Johnny Cash", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601370631381754895396381", "question": "In the 1990 film \"Home Alone\", Joe Pesci's character, Harry Lime, was named after\u00a0a character from\u00a0which Orson Welles' film?", "answer": "The Third Man", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae4c", "question": "In 1853, what country sold the US land, in what was known as the Gadsden Purchase?", "answer": "Mexico", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fea471bff048f679a45aba9", "question": "How many coulombs does one ampere-hour equal?", "answer": "3,600 Coulombs", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59071d5e3745b36be73039d7", "question": "What operation brought over 1,500 German scientists, engineers and technicians following the end of World War II to the US to aid in military research?", "answer": "Operation Paperclip", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388be", "question": "What food of the three bears did Goldilocks eat?", "answer": "Porridge", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff1450ab0ee8c595b6d39b8", "question": "What was Rodgers and Hammerstein's first Broadway musical?", "answer": "\"Oklahoma!\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe9f4c6ff048f679a45aacb", "question": "Lockiophobia is fear of what?", "answer": "Childbirth", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa0a", "question": "What is the capital of Suriname?", "answer": "Paramaribo", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fecce80ec223966ae8f88b0", "question": "Who did not attend the 1977 premiere of \"Star Wars: A New Hope\"?", "answer": "George Lucas", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4a4", "question": "How many bones are there in the human skull?", "answer": "22", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8cc", "question": "Burning potassium has what color flame?", "answer": "Purple", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe65e5b1f3c0ead6880d62a", "question": "In the 12th chapter of the \"Book of Revelation\", which angel leads a battle against a dragon?", "answer": "Michael", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a8", "question": "What song is most famous for its suggestive chorus of \"Voulez-vous coucher avec moi (ce soir)\"?", "answer": "Lady Marmalade", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390e1", "question": "What year was Ben Jonson's \"The Alchemist\" first performed?", "answer": "1610", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ad7e7e0b24f84e0b9f9ffc0", "question": "Which state surrounds the Australian Capital Territory?", "answer": "New South Wales", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6f9", "question": "Hollywood is a district of what US city?", "answer": "Los Angeles", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5b323514bf195a31e15d73ab", "question": "Sergey Bubka has set a world record in which field event over 30 times?", "answer": "Pole Vault", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392e5", "question": "In \"Rocky 3\" what does Apollo Creed give as a gift before he fights \"Clubber\" Lang?", "answer": "Boxing trunks", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cc9", "question": "What keyboard instrument with steam whistles was named for a mythological Greek muse?", "answer": "Calliope", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe0e47ffcbed638185eaa29", "question": "The Wichita Mountains can be found in which U.S. state?", "answer": "Oklahoma", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5af25190b63e5727cf5a4839", "question": "By what name do Germans refer to Austria?", "answer": "\u04e6sterreich", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1b1", "question": "What instrument family does the French Horn belong to?", "answer": "Brass", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60173cac44491cbd7c5a17a7", "question": "How did Saturday get its name?", "answer": "Saturday is named for Saturn. The word is derived from S\u00e6turnesd\u00e6g\u00a0in Old English,\u00a0dies Saturni\u00a0in Latin and samedi\u00a0in French.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b91b", "question": "What does the abbreviation \"AT&T\" stand for?", "answer": "American Telephone and Telegraph Company", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a851", "question": "What site is the home to the famous Intihuatana stone?", "answer": "Machu Picchu", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acd9", "question": "Which president had a swimming pool installed in the White House?", "answer": "Franklin Roosevelt", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5989acf0cb8751d53e7d760d", "question": "What is the collective noun for a group of ruffs?", "answer": "A hill", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b581", "question": "What year was the first iPad released?", "answer": "2010", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a4a957561d1b4d384d5d67a", "question": "Who, or what, was the \"First Reich\"?", "answer": "The Holy Roman Empire", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b19", "question": "What is the first book of the New Testament?", "answer": "The Gospel According to St. Matthew", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5f2", "question": "On which river does Washington D.C. stand?", "answer": "The Potomac", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c720", "question": "What part of the human body experiences different growth rates called anagen, catagen, and telogen?", "answer": "The hair", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a5c", "question": "According to his elementary school principal, what 1994 title character of an Oscar-winning movie had an IQ of 75?", "answer": "Forrest Gump", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58f5666033a95c66dc4fe762", "question": "What is the capital of Michigan?", "answer": "Lansing", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6015ded5fe83fe1f2a824b72", "question": "What war lasted from June 25, 1950 to July 27, 1953?", "answer": "Korean War", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b11f", "question": "The first significant gold rush in the US occurred in what state?", "answer": "North Carolina", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cacf", "question": "What is the study of the Sun called?", "answer": "Heliology", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339313", "question": "What did the license plate read on the team's response vehicle in the movie \"Ghostbusters\"?", "answer": "Ecto-1", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8ca", "question": "What country did poinsettias originally come from?", "answer": "Mexico", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcbe", "question": "What model was married to musician Marilyn Manson?", "answer": "Dita Von Teese", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133984e", "question": "What is the name of the villain from the movie \"Mulan\"?", "answer": "Shan Yu", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b541", "question": "What does Seoul, the South Korean capital mean in the Korean language?", "answer": "The Capital", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3a2", "question": "What is the official language of Egypt?", "answer": "Arabic", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c95f", "question": "What is the study of soil called?", "answer": "Pedology", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe90a3001dd7bf43be5e897", "question": "What animal has the largest brain?", "answer": "Sperm whale", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015e977fe83fe1f2a824be7", "question": "Who was the Confederate spy who became a bodyguard for the Pope at the Vatican?", "answer": "John Surratt", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6b4", "question": "What fruit is normally squeezed into a margarita?", "answer": "Lime", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc6d", "question": "What team did Brett Favre spend most of his professional football career with?", "answer": "Green Bay Packers", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c401", "question": "A male horse is known as a colt until it reaches what age?", "answer": "Five", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339975", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what is Lenny's last name?", "answer": "Leonard", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afcb", "question": "Who was the first American astronaut to enter space?", "answer": "Alan B. Shepard", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af62", "question": "What was Typhoid Mary's job?", "answer": "Cook", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7c676877e98cb977789b9", "question": "What US state is home to the Lost Sea?", "answer": "Tennessee", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd9712723c87fd04dd15e4a", "question": "Who is often credited with inventing the thermometer?", "answer": "Galileo Galilei", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5b7ffbc43a3a814d89068c6a", "question": "What year was Freddie Mercury born?", "answer": "1946", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b03e", "question": "What 1953 model of Chevrolet was first commemorated on a US postage stamp in 2005?", "answer": "The Corvette", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fecc2f4ec223966ae8f8879", "question": "Which major sports league does not let its players to wear the number 0?", "answer": "MLS", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338da7", "question": "What breed of dog is Snoopy?", "answer": "Beagle", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58c89ce0011619dd6d415480", "question": "Under what name did Eric Cartman appear as a calculus teacher in an inner-city school in season 12?", "answer": "Eric Cartmenez", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febbcbf7e83c707845b2150", "question": "What is the name of the NFL's all-star exhibition game?", "answer": "Pro Bowl", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a14a", "question": "What was Walt Disney's middle name?", "answer": "Elias", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3a0", "question": "Which fashion designer was shot dead in the summer of 1997?", "answer": "Gianni Versace", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339859", "question": "In \"Howl's Moving Castle\", Sophie tells Howl that Calcifer hired her as a what?", "answer": "Cleaning lady", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399d3", "question": "What classic sitcom character\u2019s maiden name was McGillicuddy?", "answer": "Lucy (Ricardo)", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b079", "question": "In 1996, what became the first minivan to be named Motor Trend magazine\u2019s \"Car of the Year\"?", "answer": "Dodge Caravan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399ca", "question": "What is the name of the Mob boss voiced by Joe Mantegna on the TV show \"The Simpsons\"?", "answer": "Fat Tony", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5c3e986bebfabb9c85d8a96b", "question": "Who released the album \"Tuesday Night Music Club\" in 1993?", "answer": "Sheryl Crow", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c766", "question": "What is the only mammal naturally capable of true and sustained flight?", "answer": "The bat", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b085", "question": "What world leader was awarded the 1953 Nobel Prize for Literature?", "answer": "Winston Churchill", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b885", "question": "In bowling, what would your score be if you bowled 11 strikes and a 6?", "answer": "296", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339089", "question": "Who beheaded Medusa?", "answer": "Perseus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a6d", "question": "All members of the \"Jackson 5\" were born in which US city?", "answer": "Gary, Indiana", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5be57fc05415ba52ed6f0aae", "question": "What crop is attacked by the Colorado beetle?", "answer": "Potato", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5efa96f2ccb363a2cbc5227d", "question": "How many people helped direct the 2019 season of \"The Mandalorian\"?", "answer": "5", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fedd8a96ce05a3942286d72", "question": "What is the name of the highly-entertaining main villain of \"The Matrix\"?", "answer": "Agent Smith", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca13", "question": "What is a group of snipe called?", "answer": "A wisp", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe6994d20565ad31a57c743", "question": "How many men survived the sinking of the Hood by the Bismarck in World War II?", "answer": "Three", "category": "history"}, {"id": "590087395304ceedb84e8994", "question": "What drink began in Morison's drug store in Waco, Texas in 1885?", "answer": "Dr. Pepper", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133974d", "question": "What is Alecia Moore better known as?", "answer": "P!NK", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecc8feec223966ae8f8894", "question": "What lifted Frank Darabont's spirit whenever he experienced writer's block while writing \"The Shawshank Redemption\" script?", "answer": "Listening to Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart's \"The Marriage of Figaro\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a2e", "question": "What university did David Letterman graduate from in 1969 with a degree in telecommunications?", "answer": "Ball State", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe6a3c720565ad31a57c7b7", "question": "Which US President made the dog name \"Fido\" famous?", "answer": "Abraham Lincoln", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a01e", "question": "What day of the week do the Bangles wish it was in \"Manic Monday\"?", "answer": "Sunday", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5bbc906f60f0007efaba0e53", "question": "How many squares are there on the traditional \"Snakes & Ladders\" board?", "answer": "100", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf58", "question": "What do the letters A and W stand for in the \"A&W\" root beer name?", "answer": "Allen and Wright", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a67b", "question": "What bay does the San Mateo bridge cross?", "answer": "San Francisco Bay", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58b8ce2994b094db915830a5", "question": "At what age did legendary English musician, Lemmy, die in 2015?", "answer": "70", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c36a", "question": "What does the computer term WORM stand for?", "answer": "Write Once Read Many", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a351", "question": "Which is colder, the North or South Pole?", "answer": "The South Pole", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dcd", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"smorgasbord\"?", "answer": "Swedish", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe8adc101dd7bf43be5e77d", "question": "What is Cap\u2019n Crunch\u2019s first name?", "answer": "Horatio", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe4b70b06d333868d34d6f7", "question": "Refugees on which ship were refused entry to both Cuba and the U.S. in 1939?", "answer": "St. Louis", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339445", "question": "What was the name of Tom Hanks' character in the movie \"Cast Away\"?", "answer": "Chuck Noland", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015df07fe83fe1f2a824b76", "question": "What revolution resulted in the overthrow of the Pahlavi dynasty?", "answer": "The Iranian Revolution", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ab2", "question": "What actress played Phoebe's mother on the TV show \"Friends\"?", "answer": "Teri Garr", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b453", "question": "Which 19th century monarch ordered Buckingham House to be expanded into a royal palace?", "answer": "George IV", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e6a", "question": "What does Miss Havisham constantly wear in Dickens' \"Great Expectations\"?", "answer": "Her wedding dress", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d2b", "question": "What year was the novel \"A Brave New World\" written?", "answer": "1931", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6010ca020775fa611bce67f1", "question": "Where was the first location of White Castle?", "answer": "Wichita, Kansas", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a494", "question": "Which country's capital city lies on the River Aar?", "answer": "Switzerland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5febd6c97e83c707845b216e", "question": "When was the first Masters Tournament played?", "answer": "1934", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff0b4ebe662d71a53650ff2", "question": "What educational institution was Edgar Allen Poe thrown out of?", "answer": "West Point Military Academy", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133905b", "question": "Once married to Ted Hughes, which American poet committed suicide in 1963?", "answer": "Sylvia Plath", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133962b", "question": "In what movie does Nicole Kidman play a ghost?", "answer": "The Others", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe69f9d20565ad31a57c78e", "question": "What taboo topic did Benjamin Franklin once write to the Royal Academy about?", "answer": "Flatulence", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acd0", "question": "Which US president walked down the aisle with a three-months pregnant Nancy?", "answer": "Ronald Reagan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5b1", "question": "What large island is the most western point of land in Alaska?", "answer": "Attu Island", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fea4297ff048f679a45ab7a", "question": "Which age is known as the \"Age of Fish\"?", "answer": "Paleozoic Era", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339220", "question": "Who were the principal members of the band \"The Beatles\"?", "answer": "John Lennon, Paul McCartney, George Harrison, Ringo Starr", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7d59a877e98cb97778a65", "question": "What movie depicts a society in which population and the consumption of resources are maintained by killing everyone who reaches the age of 30?", "answer": "Logan's Run", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe69fd720565ad31a57c791", "question": "Where did the biblical story of the Garden of Eden most likely take place?", "answer": "Mesopotamia", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339042", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"The Naked and the Dead\"?", "answer": "Norman Mailer", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "600cc67f6de0eb824d4052f8", "question": "Which staple food was rationed in the UK the year after the end of World War II despite having never been rationed during the war?", "answer": "Bread (Bread was rationed from 1946 to 1948 after excessive rains ruined the UK's wheat crop.)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59220648a4edfd43a087aded", "question": "Sapphires are typically what color?", "answer": "Blue", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59a552373e1c6f9840ba3193", "question": "What color flag indicates a fair throw in the shot put?", "answer": "White", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3fc", "question": "The \"Oort Cloud\" is made up of what?", "answer": "Comets", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c86c", "question": "What disease, caused by the bacteria Y. pestis, is spread by fleas and rats?", "answer": "Bubonic plague", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1d5", "question": "What was Billie Holiday's nickname?", "answer": "Lady Day", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c893", "question": "What does the Schmidt index measure?", "answer": "Pain of insect stings", "category": "science"}]